[Music]
hi everyone this is Ravi welcome to
trien Taska automation
tutorial so this is our lesson 16 in
terms of Advanced Training and this is
our lesson
31 in terms of overall automation
tutorial so in this
lesson I'm going to teach you how can we
take screenshot
automatically Whenever there is a
failure in your test Case by using
tsar and I'm also going to teach you how
can we take
screenshot on demand whenever it is
required by using tricentis
toas please do subscribe to the channel
click on icon you'll receive
notifications whenever I publish more
videos so without delay let us jump onto
the system and start working on
tricentis TSA automation
to so this is my trient tasa what I'm
going to do I'm going to create one new
folder called
screenshot okay and now let us start
working on this folder I'll create one
new test
case called login
failure so as
usual we going to start working on we
are going to automate a simple login log
out functionality by using our prent
tasa sample web application which is
demo web shop okay here what I'm going
to do I want to click on login link
provide username password and click on
login button and then
just log out from the session so let us
automate that simply control T which
brings us the modules that you would
like to add ADD test either control t or
you can simply right click and click on
ADD test here I want to call Top menu
because top menu will be having all the
options that you would like to click on
so here I want to click on login
right so before you click on login First
you need to open your url right so for
that let
us call a standard module control
T standard module called open URL okay
this is my standard
module and bring this to the first this
is my first provide the
URL here once once you open the URL I'm
clicking on
login once I click on login I need to
provide credentials for this simply on
login page so this is my login
page so here I need to provide my
username which is my email
ID and I have to provide my
password
and then click on login buttton right as
soon as you click on login button then
you're going to click on log out button
so what I'm going to do CR T again top
menu and
here this time I'm going to click log
out okay and now we going to close the
browser again it is standard module
called close browser so this is my
standard
module so here what is the browser name
it is demo
star okay so now we have completed
automating our login log out
functionality so here before I run so
first of all I have provided my password
as a wrong
password now let us run this and see
what happens okay
okay simply run this in
scratchbook so it opens your url right
and then it clicks on login
link and then it is going to enter your
username password and click on login now
because we provided wrong password it
throws an error now it is trying to
identify log out link but it will not be
able to identify TSA will not be able to
identify that's why the test case is
going to fail so your test case is
failed because could not find the link
log out okay fine so now let's assume I
want to take a screenshot
Whenever there is a login so as soon as
I enter my URL let us enter the URL as
soon as I click on login I want take a
screenshot of login page let's say I
want to take a screenshot of each page
as soon as I landed right so how can we
do that for that let us
simply insert a step and
call take screenshot tbox take
screenshot which is a standard module
which comes along with your
prosc call this take screenshot standard
module and here
you can specify the environment either
you want to specify it as a desktop or
mobile we are executing on desktop
that's why I want to select as desktop
and what is the directory that you want
to store I want to store the screenshot
in this
directory this is my directory what I
did is actually I just simply created
one empty folder called screenshot okay
so I want to store the screenshot in
this
directory simply go here
and provide the
path and now what is the file name that
you want to keep I want to keep the file
name as
screenshot screenshot and
here okay I'll do one thing screenshot
let's name this
as
screenshot so if I run this it's going
to store the screenshot let's bring this
I want to put this immediately after
after login clicking on login so I
clicked on login here and I want to
place here as soon as you click on login
I want to take a screenshot but now if
you see the file name is hardcoded I
don't want to use the file name
hardcoded file name I want to insert the
date function date time see you have a
date
time curly braces open open curly braces
date time close curly braces what it
will do is going to create the
file
with
screenshot space it gives you the date
and time stamp to the file so now let us
simply run this now
okay run this in
your okay right click and run in
scratchback so now we'll
[Music]
see it's going to run click on
login as soon as you click on login it
should take a
screenshot yes now it should take a
screenshot and perform other actions
okay so we are not taking screenshot on
failure but anyway so we are taking a
screenshot on demand screenshot I want a
screenshot and so and so step I just
inserted a screenshot okay if you see
here if you go back to your test results
here your screenshot
is
successful the screenshot was
successfully created where these are the
detail this is where the screenshot
should store so let us go to that path
so if you go to this path see you have a
screenshot as soon as you click on
login see this is your screenshot so
let's close this now so I want to take
screenshot Whenever there is a failure
in test case how can we do that so now
we understand how can you take
screenshot on demand but now I want to
take a
screenshot Whenever there is a failure
in t case I don't know when but whenever
there is a failure I want to take a
screenshot how can we achieve that so
for that you need to go to settings go
to projects go to
settings and in
settings you need to go to
tbox so it is just loading all the
settings so you need to expand tbox and
under
logging you have a folder called
screenshots here you need
to enable make screenshot on failed test
steps you can select off till now it is
off either detection failure or
verification failure I want to take a
screenshot Whenever there is a
verification failure
okay that's why I'm going to select that
as verification F and screenshot
directory if you see my environment is C
Colon c
colon slash TOS setup toas Commander
it's a default
screenshot path you can change this
particular path you can provide your
path whatever you want but I want to
keep it
as
default and here you can
select the screenshot format the
screenshot should be stored in jpeg PNG
bitmap or GI whatever I want to save the
screenshot in jpeg okay so I'm going to
leave that as it is and then close it
now let us run
our test case again now okay let us run
the test
case
so it opened your website now this time
it is going to take a screenshot on
demand whatever we inserted first and
whenever test case is failed it
automatically takes a screenshot so now
we want to see now so the test case is
failed as soon as you click on
login now let us see the
results
so if you see
here this is our earlier screenshot that
we introduced and if you see here log
out see this log out so basically it
could not find out the log
out and you can see here
details system drawing bit map so
basically there is some bit map that has
been taken by your trient Tas how can
you see that so we cannot see in
scratchbook you need to execute the test
case in execution list to see the
screenshot so let us go to your
execution list let us create a
quick execution
list
screenshot and let me simply pull this
and drop it
into the execution
list now I want to execute this
particular execution list let us run
this now let me close
this right click
[Music]
and okay so now it clicks on login
enters yes now it should take your
screenshot on failure one step is failed
so there your screenshot will be shown
show let us simply bring this here
okay here
and let us expand your execution
results here if you
see our first screenshot is this which
is your as soon as you click on login
correct and now your second screenshot
is this when your test case it is unable
to click on log out and you should see
the error message see
here I can see the error message why it
is failed because my login is not
success that's why it is not able to
find out log
out right so you can see both the
screenshots and the screenshot is saved
in your local machine also so whenever
there is a failure tasa will take
screenshot automatically and here in
this step we are instructing tasa to
take a screenshot on demand correct so
these are the two ways you can take the
screenshots by using trient Tas so if
you have any queries leave your queries
in the comment box I'll try to respond
to your
queries oh you all understand the
concept of taking screenshot in two
different methods by using Trion TOs
please do subscribe to the channel click
on Bell icon you'll receive
notifications whenever I publish more
videos thank
[Music]
you